Franklin Jin Full Stack Developer

E-mail: franklinjin229@gmail.com Location: Jackson, CA 95640, USA A full stack developer with 8+ years of experience, a skilled professional who possesses expertise in both front-end and back-end development technologies. I am capable of working on all layers of a web application, from the user interface to the database, and am familiar with various programming languages such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, Python, and more. Well-versed in web development frameworks, such as Angular, React, Next, Node.js, GraphQL, and Blockchain. Additionally, I have a thorough understanding of software development methodologies, deployment practices, and have experience with DevOps, cloud computing, and other related tools and technologies.

Work Experience

Full Stack Developer • Rentalcars

Oct 2021 - Jan 2023

- Designed project architecture using React JS, Redux, Node.js and TypeScript.
- 2 dashboards and advertisement pages using MUI, Tailwind CSS, Sass etc.
- Quick search engine queries and dynamic weighting of search terms for finding the best way to go to a purpose and the nearest drivers for customers.
- Make changes to already existing WordPress sites using Divi Builder such as CreditExpress.
- Increase the popularity of the site 40% by implementing flexible rentals.

Technologies: React JS, Vue JS, React Native, Redux, Vuex, Node.js, MongoDB, AWS, MUI, Tailwind CSS, Sass, TypeScript, Redux saga, Redux thunk, Java, Kotlin

Smart Contract Developer • Compute Coin Network

Feb 2020 - Sep 2021

- Defi contract implementation using Pancakeswap DEX protocol on Binance Smart Chain.
- ERC721, ERC1155 NFT contracts development with on-chain metadata.
- Development of Solidity smart contracts for NFT lending and renting.
- Participated in the ERC20 token swap project using the Uniswap V2 protocol.
- NFT marketplace using Cosmos SDK(Based on NFT, Bank, Gov modules) and Ignite CLI.
- Frontend integration to interact with smart contracts using Web3.js and Ethers.js.
- P2E NFT Game contract development based on Tron and Ethereum Network.

Technologies: Solidity, Rust, Ethereum, Tron, Solana, Cosmos SDK, Ignite CLI, Coswasm.js, Web3.js, DAO, DEX, Defi, Uniswap, Pancakeswap

Senior Software Engineer • ACWA

Feb 2019 - Jan 2020

- Turned the climate predicting process into an automatic process and increased the correctness 70% by using openweathermap api integration.
- Increased the popularity of the site to 40% by implementing drought response.
- Increased page loading speed 30% by improving back-end logic and streaming using Node.js and MongoDB.
- Updated the database design(20 tables) and migrated 4.5M+ records into new formatted tables, integrated with Guesty, Twillio and Google Firebase APIs for 6 months and deployed to AWS.
- Created a gaming platform, through the API connected to provider's games, with Node js., HTML and MySQL.

Technologies: Angular JS, React JS, Vue JS, WordPress, .NET, C#, WPA, MongoDB, AWS, API Integration, Redux, JavaScript, TypeScript, Tailwind CSS, React Native, Flutter

Ħ





App Developer • LanzaTech

Mar 2018 - Jan 2019

- Increased the purity of products 20% and decreased bugs 30% in the production process.
- Displayed and got various data by using integration of various signals from sensors by using Node.js.
- Implemented chatting and alert function between team members and error alert to admin using socket.io.
- Gave users a 100% remote experiment possibility at anytime and anywhere.

Technologies: React Native, WordPress, Node.js, MongoDB, JavaScript, Kotlin, Java, Swift, CSS

Frontend Developer • Simtech Development

Apr 2016 - Feb 2018

- Developed 15 front-end pages on 2 websites using HTML, CSS, PHP and Javascript.
- Improved the asynchronous api integration at the front-end using async, await and Promise.
- Increase page loading speed 40% by using a single page application on 3 websites.

Technologies: PHP, Laravel, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Figma, Photoshop

Education



Malaysia University of Science and Technology Computer Science(Bachelor's Degree)

2010 - 2014

Skills Languages

- React JS & Angular JS React native & Flutter
- Kotlin & Swift & Java
- Node.js & Express .NET & C#
- WordPress & Vue JS
- Redux & Vuex
- Blockchain
- Solidity
- GraphQL
- SQL & Mongo DB
- AWS, Oracle, Moralis & Alchemy JavaScript & TypeScript MUI, Tailwind CSS & Ant Design

• English - Fluent

Powered by CakeResume

